We'll open up for questions.
>> All righty. Thank you. Um nice to meet
all of you. Uh it's been a pretty good
night here with uh getting uh Dunker
boy. Um good football player. Um you
know, they're so well coached at Iowa.
They come out, they have established pad
level and footwork. Got a lot of respect
for that uh football program and the
people who run it. Um, but to be able to
get a guy like him, a big powerful kid
that has position flexibility,
um, and has shown leadership and his
play, his play style, uh, is really,
really unique. And also from his
standpoint of, uh, you know, you always
look for guys that are first in the line
doing things, um, that are challenging
or different, like he did at the Senior
Bowl. he was first in the line to go and
do new drills and things like that. So,
um you know, I'm sure there's some
leadership qualities there, too. But
we're very excited to have him and and
to add to the O line room.
>> Questions?
>> Tackle, guard, both?
>> Uh we're going to we'll get him in here
and take a look at him. I think at this
point, um he'll be in the guard position
and tackle will be his second probably
position. But, uh, again, you know, when
you get players like this, um, um, you
can always try to figure out which way
he's going to go. You have to put them
in somewhere to start, right? And, uh, a
lot of times big things like this can
surprise you and and sometimes they work
themselves out. So, competition is good
and in those areas. So, um, uh, yeah,
but he'll play he'll play probably end
up playing a little bit of both, but
primarily guard. Coach, what did his
attitude and appearance tell you about
him?
>> Uh, he's an aggressive kid. I mean, he
is um focus and intent is is is really u
capturing. I mean, it projects onto the
onto the field as well. Um, just a very
serious person, but I think also, you
know, the fact that he um so seamlessly
went into guard at the at the senior
bowl really made it very appealing. Um
there's not a lot of big pe big thick
people like that that can pull and and
and match the strength that he has.
>> Anyone else?
>> James, so much about offensive line is
synergy, guys fitting together, playing
together. Was it challenging for you to
try to add pieces to an offensive line
that you're just getting to learn
yourself?
>> That's a you know, that's a really good
question and that and that is uh a
function of being new to the group and
especially such a young group. Um uh but
I'll echo what Omar, our general
manager, and coach McCarthy uh say. You
can never have enough big guys in the
room. And um I think that that that is
uh number one, it's very healthy for
competition. Number two, you get an
opportunity to look at, as you said,
combinations and who's playing with who
and and those type of things. is I think
it gives you an opportunity to really be
able to move people in and out, up and
down, um, left and right, and to really
give everyone a chance to really, you
know, see what they can do and and
express themselves and their talent. And
I think that's so important, but it is
harder to do that when you don't have,
you know, the type of people we have in
that room. and every one of those those
guys in there that we've worked with so
far um at the at the mini camp we just
had and and so forth. And it's going to
be fun to get on the grass and them too
for about an hour. I think the workouts
are now. Um um that whole evaluation and
and consistency with fundamentals and
what we're going to be asking them to do
that will really, you know, set the
template uh down the road. But I I don't
think that coach or anyone expects us to
be in a big hurry to just start naming
people and stuff like that. We have to
see them them play and then uh we don't
play the game in pajamas. We got to wait
till we get our helmets and shoulder
pads on too. So to
>> your knowledge, have you ever coached a
hay bale toss champion? And uh can that
how are those skills transferable to
playing offensive blocks? Well, I tell
you I was I'm a country boy myself, so
I've done the hay bell costs. Uh I was
not a champion, though. No, no, far from
it. I could I was got my hay hooks. We
could be on opposite, but that's anyway.
But he's uh Yeah, of course it does. I
mean, it's hip flexion. It's It's like
doing a power clean and you got to
correlate everything with your knees all
the way up to your upper body and and
when you're Hay Bell champion, you're
always punching. So, he's getting pass
blocking reps. I'm sure he's been doing
that for a long time.
>> Max two more stand out mean Max. What do
you like about Max?
>> But what I like about Max, um, you know,
he's just an ultra athletic player
that's, um, just scratching the surface.
I mean, you know, the limited, uh, uh,
time that he's been in a football
uniform um, and the way that he has
translated that to what he performed,
you know, did this last season. I mean,
when you don't give up any sacks in a
season, that's at a very competitive
level in the Big 12 against some really
good football players and good edge
rushers. That tells you one thing, he's
productive. But not only he's
productive, but
you know, with technique and
fundamentals and and also just his
football intelligence and awareness
um and just playing the game is just
going to increase. So, we're very
excited about him.
>> Along those lines, I mean, you guys had
uh, you know, on the right side of the
line, three guys also on their rookie
deals. You guys take two linemen, you
know, the first couple of days. Does
that just add to your excitement with
with a bunch of exciting young guys to
get really in there and get to work with
these guys in the coming weeks?
>> Um, I don't Can you ask the question
again? I don't really understand the
question. Well, well, with with with the
youth on the right side of the line with
guys like Mason and Zack and Troy and
you guys take two guys tonight, does
that just add to your excitement with
the amount of, you know, young talent
you have at your disposal to really get
to work with them in the coming weeks?
>> Oh, absolutely. And and really, quite
frankly, everybody in that room that's
been added, I mean, this this is a young
group. I mean, I think the oldest one is
as a seven maybe going into his year,
Driscoll. And um but he hasn't played a
lot either. I mean, so and we had Brock
Hoffman, added him and and and and the
free agency and and some other guys are
very uh talented young people. We have
we have enough people in there now where
the competition is exciting. Yeah, it
is. And really the makeup of that room
is as such that it's almost like they
want that competition. It's not a thing
where everybody's going, "Oh I'm
sorry. Oh, shoot. I'm sorry." Like,
yeah. Um, that's one, right? Um, let me
back that up. It's not like they're a
bunch of guys are going, "Oh, no. We we
drafted this or we drafted this." I I
would be very shocked if that is the
case. I mean, those guys are very
headstrong and very, you know, secure in
why they're here and the competition.
Um, and and they understand what's what
is it what's at stake. And that's a good
thing. Everyone's going to be better for
that. and I need to be better as a coach
and Jarry and I and and Eric will will
do a good job as as we can with that and
and make sure we give them everything
they need.
>> All right. Thanks, coach. Thank you.